<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Slow and Steady</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Slow and Steady</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:56:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding your financial balance</title>
      <link>/posts/balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:56:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/balance/</guid>
      <description>Not all debt is bad debt, but you have to find your financial balance. When you have controlled debt like a mortgage you can find balance in your monthly budget. When you have uncontrolled debt like a credit card you’ll never find your financial balance.
So how can you tell the difference between controlled and uncontrolled debt? It all comes down to interest.
With a mortgage you’re buying back a little bit of your home every month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three guaranteed ways to make money in the stock market</title>
      <link>/posts/storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:49:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/storm/</guid>
      <description>There are only three guaranteed ways to make money in the stock market:
 Get lucky Cheat Be large enough to make your own weather  Luck is hard to come by. Even the smartest hedge fund managers eventually run out of luck. Look at famous fund managers like Nassim Taleb. As smart as they are, their luck only lasts so long.
Cheating is risky. Trading on insider information or attempting to control markets just isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to spot a bad investment</title>
      <link>/posts/lemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:48:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lemon/</guid>
      <description>Lemons are everywhere. When you buy a used car you can look for rust and bald tires, but how do you spot a financial lemon?
There are three simple steps:
 Don&amp;rsquo;t invest in companies you don&amp;rsquo;t understand. Every company has documents explaining how they make money. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to you then don&amp;rsquo;t invest in it. Watch out for companies that promise returns. All investing involves risk. Any company that guarantees returns can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much should you save?</title>
      <link>/posts/saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:47:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/saving/</guid>
      <description>We all know that saving money is important. You need to keep something back for a rainy day and for retirement. But how much money should you save?
This is a tricky question because there’s no simple right answer. Unforeseen expenses are going to happen. Your sink will explode, your washing machine will melt down, and you’re going to back your car into that dumpster at the end of your parking lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the ladder to financial freedom</title>
      <link>/posts/ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:45:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ladder/</guid>
      <description>Your first financial goal can’t be a big house, a yacht, or a fast car. Those are nice, but they can come later. Your first financial goal is to sleep well at night.
Financial freedom doesn’t mean buying anything you want. It means being free from worry. It means knowing that you’re OK. That your bills won’t overwhelm you and that you&amp;rsquo;re living well without living in debt.
Slow and Steady is a system to build your financial freedom one step at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to spot a bad investment</title>
      <link>/posts/plant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 08:45:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/plant/</guid>
      <description>Growing a garden takes patience. You provide good soil, water, and enough sun, but the plants will choose when to grow. Your financial future is the same way.
Building your financial independence takes time. Some months will make a big difference and others will feel like a step backwards. Stay slow and steady and you&amp;rsquo;ll get there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>